Frank Bowden Chilton papers, Inclusive: 1800-1964, undated, Bulk: 1887-1933
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Frank Bowden Chilton papers
Inclusive: 1800-1964, undated, Bulk: 1887-1933
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
203
Chilton, Frank Bowden, 1845 - 1926
18 document boxes and 8 oversize boxes
The Frank Bowden Chilton papers contain correspondence, subject files, artifacts, photographs, scrapbooks, and collected materials. Much of the collection has to do with the post-Civil War Confederate reunion movement.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Frank Bowden Chilton was born on 1845 February 7 in Marion, Alabama, to Reverend Thomas and Louisa Chilton. Reverend Thomas Chilton, in addition to being a Baptist minister, was also an attorney, politician, and co-author of Davy Crockett's autobiography. The Chilton family moved to Houston, Texas, around 1851.
At the beginning of the Civil War in 1861, Frank Chilton enlisted in Company H, 4th Texas Infantry. He was 16 years old. As part of the famous Hood's Texas Brigade operating in northern Virginia, Chilton's military unit became known as one of the hardest fighting and most feared units in the war. Wounded and honorably discharged in 1862 September, directly after the Peninsula Campaign, and during a severe illness, Chilton returned to Texas. After recovering, he enlisted again, and served in the 2nd Texas Cavalry under John Robert Baylor. After being wounded again, he became Post Commander and Provost Marshal at Navasota, Texas, and Ordnance Officer in Brenham, Texas.
At the end of the war, in 1865 April, Frank Chilton married Annie Briscoe Chilton (1844-1881). The Chilton family lived in Fort Bend County, Texas, farming and operating a steam mill and cotton gin. Frank Chilton read law and was admitted to the bar in 1874. Frank and Annie Chilton had one child, Mary Louise Chilton Bryan (1877-1973), born on 1877 October 23. Annie Chilton passed away in 1881. Their second child, born in 1881, also passed away that same year.
Following the loss of his wife and child, Frank Chilton and his four year old daughter moved to Marlin, Texas. He married Emma Belle Preston Chilton (1861-1884) in 1882. They had one daughter, Annie Chilton Spann (1882-1969), born on 1882 December 6. Three months later, on 1884 March 6, Emma B. Preston Chilton passed away, leaving Frank Chilton with two daughters under 7 years of age.
Frank Bowden Chilton was heavily involved in the post-war veterans reunion movement after the Civil War. He was most involved with the Hood's Texas Brigade Association, but also participated in other Confederate veteran reunions. He led the effort to construct a monument on the Capital grounds in Austin, Texas, to Hood's Texas Brigade.
Chilton's other activities include being a member of the Board of Trustees for Waco University in 1885, delegate to the New Orleans Exposition in 1885, executive committee member of the Texas Immigration Association, and general manager of the Southern Inter-state Immigration Bureau. Both immigration organization to which he belonged sought to attract industries to Texas and other southern states.
Frank Bowden Chilton passed away in Houston on 1926 May 20 after an extended illness. He is buried in Willis Cemetery in Montgomery County, Texas.
Scope and Content
The Frank Bowden Chilton papers include a variety of materials, including correspondence, subject files, artifacts, photographs, scrapbooks, and collected materials. Many of the materials have something to do with the Civil War, including both during the war and the veterans movement after the war. Some materials documenting Chilton's personal life are also included in the collection.
Some documents from Chilton's service as a Confederate soldier in the Civil War are present in the collection. Most are official war orders, directing Chilton to take command of a post in Navasota, Texas, for example. Some letters from the front are also included.
Many of the materials in this collection have to do with the post-Civil War Confederate reunion movement. Chilton was a major figure in the reunion group Hood's Texas Brigade Association. In addition to general records about the veterans and their reunions, the collection also contains an extensive amount of material about the planning, fundraising, and erection of the memorial to Hood's Texas Brigade on the capital grounds in Austin, Texas.
Arrangement
The Frank Bowden Chilton papers came to The Texas Collection from the donor in good order. Upon arrival at The Texas Collection, materials were foldered and organized by series: Correspondence and Subject Files. At one time, the artifacts were separated from the collection and were housed elsewhere, but have been reunited with the rest of the collection.
Currently, the collection is arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, II. Subject Files, III. Photographic Materials, IV. Collected Publications, V. Scrapbooks, and VI. Artifacts.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 203.
Related Resources
Related references
Daniell, L.E. "Types of Successful Men of Texas: Biography of Captain Frank Bowden Chilton." 1890.
Find A Grave, Inc. "Annie Briscoe Chilton." Memorial #67385315. Databases. Accessed 2019 October 10.
Find A Grave, Inc. "Emma B. Preston Chilton." Memorial #189716216. Databases. Accessed 2019 October 10.
Find A Grave, Inc. "Frank Bowden Chilton." Memorial #27405524. Databases. Accessed 2019 October 10.
Find A Grave, Inc. "Rev Thomas Chilton." Memorial #35244936. Databases. Accessed 2019 October 10.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Chilton, Frank Bowden, 1845-1926.; Hood, John Bell, 1831-1879.
Subjects (Organizations)
United Confederate Veterans.
Places
Confederate States of America -- History -- Societies, etc.; Confederate States of America. Army. Texas Brigade.; Texas -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Correspondence.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Monuments.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Veterans.
Subjects
Veterans -- Confederate States of America.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Cultural artifacts.; Minutes (Records); Periodicals.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence, 1864-1926, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains letters to and from Frank Bowden Chilton to family members and friends. Many of them contain information on the reunions of Hood's Texas Brigade Association, from arranging the annual reunions to compiling information on members about their service in the war. This series is in good condition.
  - A, 1888-1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1887-1923, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Berryman, H.W., 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bruckenridge, G.W., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bernard, George, A., 1908-1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - C, 1888-1922 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - D, 1902-1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - E, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - F, 1907-1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - G, 1869-1913, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gaston, W.H., 1907-1911 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Goree, E.K., 1906-1909, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Goree, E.K., 1908-1911 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Goree, E.K., 1911 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Goree, E.K., 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - H, 1864-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hamby, William R., 1909-1910, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hamby, William R., 1908-1910 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hamby, William R., 1908-1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hamby, William R., 1907-1909, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hamby, William R., 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Hamby, William R., 1910 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hamby, William R., 1910 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hamby, William R., 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hill, W. T., 1907-1912 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Hill, W. T., 1909-1910 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hill, W. T., 1910-1916, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hood, Margaret M., 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hunter, J. T., 1907-1910, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hunter, J. T., 1909-1910, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hunter, J. T., 1910-1913 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hunter, J. T., 1912-1916, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - J, 1906-1918 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - K, 1908-1924 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Kirby, John H., 1907-1909 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kirby, John H., 1909-1910 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kirby, John H., 1910-1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kirby, John H., 1912-1916 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - L, 1908-1915 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Littlefeild, George W., 1888-1911 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - M, 1907-1912 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - M, 1912-1923 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Murdock, Mrs. Moore, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - N, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - P, 1903-1911, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Polly, J. B., 1907-1909 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Polly J. B., 1908-1909 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Polly J. B., 1910-1911 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Powell, R. M., 1888, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Powell, R. M., 1888-1911, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - R, 1910-1924 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - S, 1864-1911, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - S, 1911-1923 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - T, 1907-1919 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - U, 1897-1898 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - W, 1864-1909, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - W, 1909-1924 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Y, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Civil War, 1864 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General, 1917 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 2)
- Subject Files, 1834-1964, undated; 2
  This series contains various files on people, places, groups, and events during Chilton's life. Of note are the files on Hood's Texas Brigade and the Hood's Texas Brigade Association, immigration, Civil War topics, and the Colorado Lake Chautauqua Association. This series is in fair condition.
  - Baylor University and College, 1887-1927 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Campbell (T. M.) Campaign for Governor, 1905-1909 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chilton, Thomas, 1834-1946, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chilton, Thomas, 1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Civil War, 1864-1920, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Colorado Lake, Chautauqua Association, 1893-1904, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Colorado Lake, Chautauqua Association, 1892-1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Daffan, Katie, 1908-1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Daffan, Katie, 1911-1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Davis (“Cyclone”) Controversy, 1916, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Davis (“Cyclone”) Controversy, 1916, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Davis, Jefferson, 1889-1908, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Davis, Winnie, 1889, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fraternal Organizations, 1904-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gettysburg, 1903-1909, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Tom Green Monument, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Immigration, 1888-1889 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Immigration Programs, Guides, 1888, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Immigration Programs, Guides, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Immigration Programs, Guides, 1887-1910, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Immigration Programs, Guides, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Immigration Programs, Guides, 1912-1933 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Johnston, Albert Sidney, 1892, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Johnston, Joseph E., undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Memorials to Confederate Dead, Poetry, 1865-1907, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Nugent, C. W., 1912 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Reagan, John, 1865-1907 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Slavery, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - New South, 1906-1916, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Prohibition, 1915, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Stone Mountain, Georgia Monument, 1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Terry’s Texas Rangers, 1907, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Texas History, 1837, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Tompkins (Sallie) Memorial Fund, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - United Confederate Veterans, 1924-1925, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - United Confederate Veterans, 1912-1924, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1889-1936, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1911-1964, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - World War I and Peace, 1917-1919, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Certificates, 1848-1926 (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 1p)
  - Certificates, 1905 (Box 17 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Certificates and Appointments, 1879-1925, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, General (1 of 2), 1870-1962 (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, General (1 of 2), 1870-1962 (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, General (1 of 3), 1911-1923 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, General (2 of 3), 1911-1923 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, General (3 of 3), 1911-1923 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Civil War, 1865-1906 (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Civil War (1 of 2), 1900-1925 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Civil War (2 of 2), 1900-1925 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Hood’s Texas Brigade Association (1 of 3), circa 1917 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Hood’s Texas Brigade Association (2 of 3), circa 1917 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, Hood’s Texas Brigade Association (3 of 3), circa 1917 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, U-Boat, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, Religious, circa 1956 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, Rations, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, Letters to the Editors, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Financial Materials, 1889-1989, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Maps, undated (Box 26 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - F. B. Chilton, 1888-1926 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - F. B. Chilton, 1865-1890, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - F. B. Chilton, 1871-1910, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Colorado Lake Chautauqua, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - F. B. Chilton—Addresses (1 of 2), 1923, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - F. B. Chilton—Addresses (2 of 2), 1880 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - F. B. Chilton—Addresses, Published (1 of 3), Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - F. B. Chilton—Addresses, Published (2 of 3), Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - F. B. Chilton—Addresses, Published (3 of 3), Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - F. B. Chilton—Confederate Records (1 of 2), 1864-1865, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - F. B. Chilton—Confederate Records (2 of 2), 1865, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - F. B. Chiton—Photographs, 1909-1910, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - F. B. Chilton—Scrapbook, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, 1872-1917, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, 1908-1916, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—B. V. Arnold Controversy, 1916-1917 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Baby of Hood’s Brigade, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - “Unveiling and Dedication of Monument to Hood’s Texas Brigade Association”, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - “Unveiling and Dedication of Monument to Hood’s Texas Brigade Association” Notes, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - “Unveiling and Dedication of Monument to Hood’s Texas Brigade Association” Notes, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - “Unveiling and Dedication of Monument to Hood’s Texas Brigade Association” Manuscript, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, by J. B. Polly, 1908-1911, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee—General, 1907-1910, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee, 1861-1908, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee, 1908-1909 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee, 1909-1910 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee, 1910-1911, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee, 1910-1912, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Committee — Financial Records, 1908-1912, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Dedication, Austin (1 of 2), 1910 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Monument Dedication, Austin (2 of 2), 1910 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—William Townsend Campaign for Governor, 1864 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (1 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (2 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (3 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (4 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (5 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (6 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (7 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association—Minutes of Reunion (8 of 8), 1872-1905 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Waco Reunion, 1889 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Calvert Reunion, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Corsicana Reunion, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Somerville Reunion, 1906 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Navasota Reunion, 1907 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Jacksonville Reunion, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Jefferson Reunion, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Austin Reunion, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Cameron Reunion, 1911 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Cameron Reunion (1 of 2), 1911 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Cameron Reunion (2 of 2), 1911 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Calvert Reunion, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Temple Reunion, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Ennis Reunion, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Floresville Reunion, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Rockdale Reunion, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Alto Reunion, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Bryan Reunion (1 of 4), 1919-1925 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Bryan Reunion (2 of 4), 1919-1925 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Bryan Reunion (3 of 4), 1919-1925 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Association, Reunions—Bryan Reunion (4 of 4), 1919-1925 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—General (1 of 2), 1908-1912 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—General (2 of 2), 1908-1912 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company A (1 of 2), 1909-1911 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company A (2 of 2), 1909-1911 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company B, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company D, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company E, 1908-1924, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company F, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company G, 1911-1913 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment-Company H, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company I, 1907-1911 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company K, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company L, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—First Regiment—Company M, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—General, 1907-1911 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company A, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company B, 1911-1912 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company C, 1907-1968 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company D, 1909-1911 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company E, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company F, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company G, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company H (1 of 4), 1861-1915 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company H (2 of 4), 1861-1915 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company H (3 of 4), 1861-1915 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company H (4 of 4), 1861-1915 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company I, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fourth Regiment—Company K, 1861-1911 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment — Company A, 1906-1912 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company A, 1912-1918, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company B, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company C, 1908-1911 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company D, 1911-1912 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company E, 1908-1915 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company F, 1916-1924 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company F, 1861-1864 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment-Company F, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company G, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company G, 1864-1968 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company H, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company I, 1863-1912 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment-Company I, 1861-1913 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company I, 1861-1868 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company I, 1861-1868 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company I, 1861-1868 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Fifth Regiment—Company K, 1907-1911 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade—Eighteenth Regiment—Company K, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Postcards, 1939-1959, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Travel Brochures, 1941, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade Travel Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade — Rolls, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade — Action During Civil War, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade — Action During Civil War, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade — Causality Lists, 1861-1864 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Hood’s Texas Brigade — Causality Lists, 1862 (Box 13, Folder 13)